Register of the Dixy Lee Ray papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1963-1981
  - Washington State Magistrates Association
  - Washington State Medicaid Agency
  - Washington State Research Council
  - Washington State School Directors' Association
  - Washington State Thermal Power Plant Site Evaluation Council
  - Washington State University
  - Washington Women United
  - Watanabe, Taul
  - Water rights
  - Water-producing energy centers in the Middle East. See Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Studies
  - Weinberg, Alvin (Box 44)
  - Welfare
  - Western States Policy Office
  - Weyerhaeuser-Stoneway Strip Mine
  - White House Office of Science and Technology
  - Willamette River Basin
  - Women
  - Yakima Valley College
  - Yucatan coral
  - Zoology
- PACIFIC SCIENCE CENTER, 1963-1972
  - General (Box 45)
  - Accounts
  - Allied Arts of Seattle
  - Arts for Youth Council
  - Board of Trustees
  - Book and Gift Shop
  - Bylaws
  - "Challenge for Survival " See New York Botanical Garden, 1968
  - Civil defense - Facilities at the Pacific Science Center (hereafter PSC)
  - Commission on Marine Science, Engineering and Resources
  - Community Relations Committee
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological file
      - 1969
      - 1970
      - (blue copies), 1969 (Box 46)
      - (blue copies), 1970
      - 1971 (Box 47)
      - 1972
    - Personal file
      - 1963-1966
      - 1967-1969
      - 1967-1972 (Box 48)
      - 1968-1981
      - 1970-1972
  - Director's Report, 1972 (Box 49)
  - Exhibits
    - General
    - Notes of DLR
    - Scripts (2 folders)
  - Financial records
  - Future developments at the PSC - Notes of DLR
  - Interviews
  - Laboratory and classroom construction
  - Library Liaison Committee - Intermediate District IX (Box 50)
  - Mathematics
    - Advisory Committee
    - Class
  - Memoranda
  - Miscellanea
  - New York Botanical Garden - Symposium: "Challenge for Survival 1968,", 25-26 April 1968
  - Oceanographic Commission of Washington
    - General (2 folders)
    - Meetings (Box 51)
      - 1965, November 16
      - 1967
        - September 22
        - December 14
      - 1968
        - March 14
        - April 24
        - May 27
        - July 1
        - October 1
      - 1969
        - June 9
        - June 16
        - l, July 2
        - November 13
        - December 19
      - 1970 (Box 52)
        - March 26
        - May 4
        - June 5
        - July 20
        - September 3
        - October 26
        - December 4
      - 1971
        - January 4
        - February 16
        - April 16
        - May 28
        - August 6
        - September 17
        - November 1
        - December 10
      - 1972
        - January 3
        - April 7
        - June 2
        - July 28
        - October 20
  - Oceanographic Institute of Washington. See also Oceanographic Commission of Washington. Meetings (Box 53)
  - Oceanography
    - Class. See Summer Oceanography Class
    - Correspondence
  - Overall Economic Development Programs Planning Committee
  - Personnel
  - Rental policy for PSC building
  - Resignation of DLR, 1972
  - Resolutions
  - Resume of activities, 1969
  - School Advisory Committee (Box 54)
  - Science Advisory Committee (2 folders)
  - Science Council
  - Science Libraries
  - Sea Use Council
  - Sea Use Program, Cobb Seamount
  - Seattle Youth Symphony Orchestra - Pacific Northwest Camp
  - Speaking invitations (Box 55)
    - 1969
    - 1970
      - January-March
      - April-December
    - 1971 (Box 56)
      - January-May
      - June-December
    - 1972
  - Speeches and writings
  - Summer Oceanography Class (Box 57)
    - (2 folders), 1969
    - 1970
  - TE VEGA (Research Vessel) Expedition, International Indian Ocean, 1964
    - General
    - Correspondence (3 folders)
    - Cruise A (Box 58)
    - Cruise B
    - Indian language printed material
  - Television Continuity Public Relations program (2 folders)
  - Travel
  - Union agreements
  - U.S. Science Exhibit
- ATOMIC ENERGY COMMISSION, 1972-1975
  - General (Box 59)
  - Achievements of DLR as chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission (hereafter AEC)
  - Administrative matters
  - Amchitka Bioenvironmental Program
  - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission
  - Annual Report to Congress, 1974
  - Appointment of DLR
    - as member, 8 August 1972
    - as chairman, 6 February 1973
    - Congratulatory letters
  - Appointment books
  - Correspondence (Box 60)
    - Chronological file
      - 1972
        - August-September
        - October
        - November
        - December
      - 1973
        - January-May
        - September-December (Box 61)
      - 1974
        - January-June
        - (2 folders), July-December
      - 1975, January
    - Numerical file
      - Index, March 1974 - February 1975
      - A-99
      - A-199 (Box 62)
      - A-299
      - A-399
      - A-499
      - A-599
      - A-699
      - 100-199 (Box 63)
      - 200-299
      - 300-399
      - 400-499
      - 500-599
      - 600-699
      - 700-799 (Box 64)
      - 800-899
      - 900-999
    - Personal file
      - A
      - B (2 folders)
      - C (3 folders) (Box 65)
      - D
      - E
      - F
      - G
      - H (Box 66)
      - I
      - J
      - K
      - L
      - M (2 folders)
      - N (Box 67)
      - O
      - P (2 folders)
      - R (2 folders)
      - S (3 folders) (Box 68)
      - T
      - U
      - V
      - W (2 folders)
      - XYZ
  - Directory (Box 69)
  - Director of labor relations
  - Doub, William O.
    - General
    - Correspondence with Ralph Nader
  - Drewry, George E.
  - Ellwood City Industrial Council
  - "Energy and the Environment." AEC exhibit, 1972
  - Energy Research and Development Administration - Implementation Bill (2 folders)
  - Financial holdings reports of employees
  - General Advisory Committee (Box 70)
  - General Counsel
  - General Manager
  - Gifts, foreign. Register
  - Giraud, Andre. See Visits
  - Glennan, T. Keith
  - Guzzo, Louis
  - Hearings of the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, Backup book for DLR, 28 February 1973
  - Hinds, H.R.
  - Holifield, Chet
  - Hosmer, Craig
  - International agreements
  - Invitations (Box 71)
    - 1972, September-December
    - 1973
      - January-April
      - May-September
      - October-December
    - 1974
    - Acknowledgements (Box 72)
      - 1973
        - February (2 folders)
        - March
        - April
        - May
        - June (Box 73)
        - July
        - August
    - Pending reply, 1973
    - Regrets
      - A
      - B (Box 74)
      - C
      - D
      - E
      - F
      - G
      - H
      - I
      - J
      - L (Box 75)
      - M
      - N
      - O
      - P
      - R
      - S
      - T (Box 76)
      - U
      - V
      - W
      - XYZ
  - Jenkins, David
  - Kissinger initiative - Memorandum of DLR, 13 November 1974
  - McCormack, Mike - Statement on Hanford
  - Media relations
  - Meetings
  - Memoranda. See also Reading file
  - Miscellanea
  - Muntzig, Manning (Box 77)
  - Notes
  - Office of Information Services
    - General
    - Reading file
      - 1972
      - 1973
      - 1974
      - 1974 (Box 78)
    - Referrals to John Harris, director
  - Office of Management and Budget, Executive Office of the President
    - General
    - Relationship with the AEC. See also White House
      - Letter of DLR to Frank G. Zarb, 12 September 1974
      - Letter of John P. Abadessa to Robert C. Seamans, Jr., 7 December 1974
  - Omenn, Gilbert
  - Personnel (2 folders)
  - Press conferences (Box 79)
  - Press receptions
  - Press releases
  - Press schedule
  - Project Independence Advisory Committee
  - , December 1974
  - Reading file
    - 1972, September-December
    - 1973
      - January-March
      - April-June
      - July-December
  - Reading material sent to DLR and referred for reply to various staff members. Correspondence (Box 80)
    - Hargett, Minnie Earle
    - Jackson, A.W.
      - August 1981-June 1972
      - July-December 1972
      - 1973
  - Reorganization, 15 May 1973
  - Salary of DLR
  - Secretary's handbook
  - Separation clearance for DLR
  - Simon, William E.
  - Speaking and special events schedule (Box 81)
  - Speaking invitations
    - General
    - Declined and referred to B. Wood
  - Speeches (arranged alphabetically by requesting group or occasion)
    - List, 1973-1974
    - Achievement Rewards for College Scientists Foundation - "Woman of Science Award" presenta- tion, Beverly Hills, California, 22 June 1974
    - Advertising Council, Inc., Washington, D.C., 24 June 1974
    - American Bar Association, Honolulu, Hawaii, 14 August 1974
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, Tempe, Arizona, 17 June 1974
    - American Nuclear Society
      - National Topical Meeting on Nuclear Power Plants, Portland, Oregon, 26 August 1974
      - Winter Meeting, Washington, D.C., 29 October-1 November 1974
    - American Power Conference, Chicago, Illinois, 30 April 1974 (Box 82)
    - American Public Works Association, Vancouver, Washington, 3 April 1974
    - American Translators Association, Chicago, Illinois, 11-12 October 1974
    - Ames Laboratory, Ames, Iowa, 2 October 1972
    - Argonne National Laboratory, Argonne, Illinois, 19-20 October 1972
    - Associated Press Management Editors Association, Long Beach, California, 22 November 1974
    - Association of Science-Technology Centers, Columbus, Ohio, 14 November 1974
    - Atomic Industrial Forum, Washington, D.C., 29 October 1974
    - Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, (cancelled), 15-16 May 1974
    - Chicago Rotary Club, Chicago, Illinois, 8 October 1974
    - Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, California, 14 September 1973
    - Commomwealth Edison Company Engineering Conference, Delavan, Wisconsin, 11 September 1974
    - Department of Defense, Washington, D.C., 17 July 1974
    - Executive Women in Government, Washington, D.C., 15 October 1974
    - Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory dedication, Batavia, Illinois, 11 May 1974
    - Festival of the Fountains, Seattle, Washington, 26 July 1973
    - Fort St. Vrain Nuclear Power Station, Denver, Colorado, 9 February 1974
    - Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 17 April 1974
    - Government Leadership Conference, Evansville, Indiana, 9 November 1973 (Box 83)
    - Greater Los Angeles Press Club, Los Angeles, California, 11 September 1973
    - House Republican Task Force on Energy, Washington, D.C., 7 August 1974
    - Illinois Science Teachers Association, Edwardsville, Illinois, 18 October 1974
    - International Atomic Energy Agency, Vienna, Austria, 16-20 September 1974
    - International Congress of Radiation Research, Seattle, Washington, 14 July 1974
    - International Symposium on Packaging and Transporta- tion of Radioactive Materials, Miami, Florida, 24 September 1974
    - Kalamazoo College, New York City, New York, 13 June 1974
    - Ladies Home Journal - "Woman of the Year Award" presentation, New York City, New York, 8 April 1974
    - Lawrence Livermore Laboratory - Laser Fusion Building dedication, Livermore, California, 27 September 1974
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory - Scyllac dedica- tion, Los Alamos, New Mexico, 25 April 1974
    - Los Angeles Council of Engineers, Los Angeles, California, 3 October 1974
    - Lyndon B. Johnson Library - Symposium on Energy and the Environment, Austin, Texas, 11-12 November 1974
    - Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, 9 June 1974
    - Mound Laboratory, Dayton, Ohio, 30 October 1972 (Box 84)
    - National Broadcast Editorial Association, Washington, D.C., 27 June 1974
    - National Energy Youth Conference, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, 30 July-4 August 1974
    - National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 21, January 1974
    - Naval Light Weight Nuclear Power Workshop, Arlington, Virginia, 22 October 1974
    - Northern Michigan State, Marquette, Michigan, 9 August 1974
    - New York Times luncheon, New York City, New York, 29 July 1974
    - Paducah Area Office of the AEC, Paducah, Kentucky, 25 September 1972
    - Pennsylvania State University - Honorary Engineering Lecture, University Park, Pennsylvania, 26 February 1974
    - Portland State University - Environmental Sciences Program, Portland, Oregon, 5 April 1974
    - Public Relations Society of America, College Park, Maryland, 10 July 1974
    - Ripon College, Ripon, Wisconsin, 12 May 1974
    - Royal Academy of Engineering Sciences, Stockholm, Sweden, 19 September 1974
    - Sandia Laboratories - Affirmative Action Conference, Alburqueque, New Mexico, 31, January 1973 (Box 85)
    - Seattle "First Citizen's Award" presentation, Seattle, Washington, 8 March 1974
    - Seattle First National Bank, Seattle, Washington, 19 December 1974
    - Simmons College, Boston, Massachusetts, 13-14 October 1972
    - South Carolina Conference on the Status of Women, Columbia, South Carolina, 10 March 1973
    - St. Mary's College, South Bend, Indiana, 18 May 1974
    - Tennessee Society of Professional Engineers, Knoxville, Tennessee, 22 February 1974
    - 3M Technical Forum, St. Paul, Minnesota, 30 May 1974
    - Union College, Schenectady, New York, 15 June 1974
    - University of Chicago - Thirtieth Anniversary of the First Self-Sustaining Nuclear Chain Reaction (in commemoration of Enrico Fermi), Chicago, Illinois, 2 December 1972 (Box 86)
    - University of Puget Sound, Tacoma, Washington, 26 May 1974
    - University of Rochester, Rochester, New York, 21, September 1972
    - University of Texas - "The Implications of Nuclear Power in Texas" Conference, Austin, Texas, 1-2 March 1973
    - Washington, D.C. Rotary Club, Washington, D.C., 22 August 1973
    - Westinghouse Science Talent Search, Washington, D.C., 18 March 1974
    - White House Economic Conference, New Orleans, Louisiana, 23-24 September 1974
    - Widemer College, Chester, Pennsylvania, 21, March 1974
    - Women's Forum on National Security, Washington, D.C., 20 February 1973
    - World Energy Conference, Detroit, Ohio, 22-27 September 1974
    - YWCA (Box 87)
      - "Salute to Women in Business," New York City, New York, 3 October 1974
      - "1974 Gold Medal Award" presentation, Philadel- phia, Pennsylvania, 26 March 1974
  - Statements
  - Television appearances
    - "Everywoman,", 29 April 1974
    - "Kennedy and Company,", 1974
    - "Meet the Press,", 14 April 1974
    - "Mike Douglas Show," (cancelled), 29 May 1974
  - Travel
    - General
    - Schedules
      - August 1972-May 1973
      - May-December 1973
      - 1973 (Box 88)
      - 1974
    - Trips
      - Europe
        - 13-, 25 September 1973
        - l-10, October 1974
      - Iceland, 22-24 November 1973
      - Paris and London, 26-29 November 1974
      - Stockholm, 18-20 September 1974
      - Teheran, 20 May 1974
      - Vienna, 16-18 September 1974 (Box 89)
  - Visits
    - French atomic officials (Andre Giraud), 12-15 December 1974
    - Gerald Ford, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, 22 July 1974
  - White House
    - General
    - Conference on Inflation, Washington, D.C., 27-28 September 1974
    - Correspondence of DLR with
      - the President, regarding the role of the Office of Management and Budget, 9 September 1974
      - Rogers C.B. Morton, regarding the relationship between the AEC and the White House organization, 19 August 1974
- STATE DEPARTMENT, 1975
  - Appointment of DLR as Assistant Secretary for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, 29 October 1974 (Box 90)
    - General
    - Congratulatory letters
  - Appointment books
  - Appointment schedule. See also Correspondence, Chronological file (Box 91)
    - January-February, 1975
    - March-June, 1975
  - Bengelsdorf, H.
  - Bruner, David H.
  - Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs. See Establishment of
  - Confidential Statement of Employment and Financial Interests - Forms
  - Confirmation hearings of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee for DLR, 12 December 1974
  - Correspondence
    - General
    - General (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - Chronological file (including appointment schedules)
      - December 1974-January 1975
      - February-March, 1975
      - April, 1975 (Box 93)
      - May, 1975
      - June-July 1975
    - Numerical file
      - S-99
      - S-199
      - S-299 (Box 94)
      - S-399
      - S-499
      - S-599
      - S-699 (Box 95)
      - S-799
      - S-899
      - S-999
    - Personal file (Box 96)
      - A (2 folders)
      - B
      - C (2 folders)
      - D
      - E
      - F
      - G
      - H
      - I
      - J (Box 97)
      - K
      - L
      - M
      - N
      - O
      - P
      - R (2 folders)
      - S (Box 98)
      - T
      - U
      - V
      - W
      - XYZ
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare - International activities
  - Establishment of the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs (2 folders)
  - International agreements
  - Invitations (Box 99)
    - General
    - Regrets
      - B
      - C
      - D
      - E
      - F
      - G-H
      - I
      - J
      - L
      - M
      - N
      - O
      - P
      - Q-R
      - S (Box 99)
      - T
      - U-V
      - W
      - XYZ
  - Memoranda (3 folders) (Box 100)
  - Notes
  - Office of Oceans and Fisheries
  - Organizational problems related to nuclear energy
  - Personal Data Statement to be filled out by DLR (Box 10l178-180)
  - Personal Qualifications Statement - Forms
  - Personnel
  - Program and Resources Plan
  - Reading material (3 folders)
  - Resignation of DLR (Box 102)
    - General
    - Letter of Gerald R. Ford to DLR, 26 June 1975
    - Statements of support
  - Salary of DLR
  - Secretariat
  - Speaking and special events calendar and list of speeches
  - Speech material
  - Speeches (arranged alphabetically by requesting group or occasion)
    - Unidentified, on alternative energy sources
    - American Society for Engineering Education, Fort Collins, Colorado, 18 June 1975
    - American Association of University Women, Seattle, Washington, 16 June 1975
    - Association of American Foreign Service Women, Washingon, D.C., 10 April 1975
    - Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc., New York City, New York, 19 May 1975
    - COSERV Conference, Washington, D.C., 12 March 1975
    - Crichton Club, Gahanna, Ohio, 7 March 1975
    - Edison Electric Institute, Denver, Colorado, 2 June 1975
    - Federation of Americans Supporting Science and Technology, Washington, D.C., 5 March 1975
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 5 May 1975
    - Herbert H. Lehman College (The City University of New York), Bronx, New York, 4 June 1975
    - IBM luncheon, New York City, New York, 8 April 1975
    - Industrial Research Institute, Inc., White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, 30 May 1975
    - International Instrumentation Symposium, Philadel- phia, Pennsylvania, 19 May 1975
    - International Trade Conference, Seattle, Washington, 14 May 1975
    - Lehigh University, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1 May 1975
    - National Academy of Science, Washington, D.C., 24 March 1975
    - National Association of Manufacturers, Washington, D.C., 10 April 1975
    - National Energy Forum, Washington, D.C., 16 May 1975
    - National War College, Washington, D.C., 2 April 1975
    - North Pacific Fur Seal Commission, Washington, D.C., 10 March 1975
    - Smith College, Hartford, Connecticut, 25 February 1975
    - Southampton College (Long Island University), South- ampton, New York, 31 May 1975
    - Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 25 March 1975
    - University of Alaska, Anchorage, Alaska, 9 May 1975
    - University of California at Los Angeles - Facing a World of Scarce Resources Conference, Los Angeles, California, 21, March 1975
    - University of Maryland at Baltimore, Baltimore, Maryland, 29 May 1975
    - Women's Forum on National Security - "Molly Pitcher Award" presentation, Washington, D.C., 24 February 1975 (Box 103)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution, Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 18 March 1975
    - World Affairs Institute, Morgantown, West Virginia, 17 May 1975
  - Transfer of staff and equipment from the AEC to DLR's State Department office
  - Travel
    - Schedules
    - Trips
      - Europe, 13-26 April 1975
        - General
        - Copenhagen
        - Helsinki
        - London
        - Munich
        - Paris
      - New York, 25 February 1975
      - Teheran, 19-24 January 1975
- INTERIM YEARS, 1937-1981
  - Interim Years, 1975-1976 (Box 104)
  - Correspondence
    - "File 13" (letters from possibly unbalanced people, kept for the record)
    - Letters of praise and support from attendants to lectures given by DLR
  - Interviews
  - Notes
  - Publishing offers
  - Speaking engagements
    - Contracts
      - pending
      - signed - speeches given
    - Correspondence with Leigh Lecture Bureau, DLR's agent
    - Invitations (2 folders)
  - Speeches
  - Television appearances
- GUBERNATORIAL CAMPAIGNS, 1976 and 1980
  - 1976 (Box 105)
    - General
    - Announcement speech, 20 February 1976
    - Citizens' Committee for Dixy Lee Ray for Governor
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - Letters of support, including contributions (3 folders)
    - , 1976
    - Financial records
      - General (3 folders)
      - General (Box 106)
      - General (7 folders) (Box 107)
      - Accounts, final
      - Citizens' Committee (2 folders)
      - Citizens' Committee (Box 108)
      - Executive Mansion Fund (2 folders)
      - Media exposure costs
      - Office Fund bills
      - Payments in-kind (Box 109)
      - Petty cash receipts
      - Spokane
      - Sternoff, David
    - Fund-raising. See also Index cards, boxes 112-114.
    - Kelly, Andy
    - Memoranda
    - Miscellanea
    - Notes
    - Offers to help
    - Public Disclosure Commission
      - General (4 folders)
      - General (Box 110)
      - Statements
        - A-C
        - D-F
        - G-H
        - I-K
        - L-N
        - O-Q
        - R-T
        - U-W
        - X-Z
    - Requests for candidates to state their positions on various issues
    - Schedules and itineraries
    - Schrock, Richard T., Campaign director (Box 111)
    - Songs
    - Speaking invitations (4 folders)
    - Speeches, including speech notes. See also Announcement speech
    - Statements
      - of DLR
      - of other candidates
    - Stickers, flyers
    - Television appearances
    - Travel
    - Index cards listing by alphabetical order the contributors to DLR's campaign and indicating the amount they gave (Box 112)
      - A-G
      - H-O (Box 113)
      - P-Z (Box 114)
  - 1980 (Box 115)
    - General
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - Letters of support during the campaign, including contributions (2 folders)
      - Letters wishing DLR well after her defeat
        - General (6 folders)
        - A-B
        - C-D (Box 116)
        - E-F
        - G-H
        - I-J
        - K-L
        - M-N
        - O-P
        - Q-R
        - S-T (Box 117)
        - U-V
        - W-Z
    - Declaration and affidavit of candidacy of DLR
    - Defeat in state open primary, 18 September
      - Clippings
      - Interviews
    - Democratic State Party
    - Endorsements, statements of support
    - Fund-raising
    - Guidelines
    - Invitation log
    - Johnson, C. Montgomery, Campaign director
    - King County Dixy Lee Ray Advisory Committee
    - Lundstrom, Boyd
    - Magnuson, Warren G.
    - Media coverage
    - Memoranda of Louis Guzzo to DLR
    - Miscellanea (Box 118)
    - Offers to help
    - People for Governor Dixy's Re-election Committee. Issues of
    - Polls, caucuses
    - Public Disclosure Commission
    - Republican State Committee of Washington
    - Requests for candidates to state their positions on various issues
    - Root, Robert
    - Schedules and lists of major campaign events
    - Songs